After we have learned about the insertion sorting algorithm and we have seen the animation and we get
deeply in its complexity.
Let's learn about implementing the insertion algorithm insertion sort algorithm in sea language and
next video, we are going to solve exercise that that will implement the insertion salt algorithm in
Java.
So we start by including the math, but the action as to the IO detach and let's create a function to
sort an array using the insertion stop.
So the void insertion sort took into the perimeter of the array that we are going to sort and end,
and the size of this array will create entirely the key and we start to making an outer loop for I equals
to one Islas then and going through all the elements by using iteration I plus plus.
We make and we assigned the key valuable is equal to the array, and then Jay is equal to I'm minus
one.
We decreased by one.
And we assign it to now move elements of array at index from zero till I minus one that are greater
than the key to one position ahead of their current position.
So we are picking them and we are comparing it with the sort that they're considered sought to position
elements of that.
We have a wide loop j greater than or equal to zero.
And Jay a sortie and array at index greater than the key then array at Index J +1 equal to array at
the next J and J equals to J minus one with degrees j by one.
So in this case, we are comparing it with considered sorted elements.
Array at Index J Plus one equals the key by assigning it.
OK.
This is the insurgency.
If you tell it the function to print and everyday, we have seen this function previously.
And I'm not going to talk about that.
Just a for loop that goes through all the elements of that.
And print them.
So we need a driver program to test the insurgents sort we made in Iraq.
We get the size of the array and store it inside and.
And we called the function in certain insertion sort by passing there that we are going to sort and
the size of its.
And we print the array after sorting.
So this is how we make the insertion sort algorithm and see.
So as a recap, what we have done here is making a for loop.
This is the out of the loop that goes that separates the array and start considering the first element
is or the first section is sorted and the second section is unsorted and start picking from this unsorted
one and comparing it with this sorted one by using the wide loop.
And when we have an element that greater than we assign it, greater than or equal to zero and greater
than equal to the key.
Then we assign and make the swap here.
And this is the algorithm behind the insertion circuit.
Please go back to the animation video in the previous videos, and let's learn about the insertion story
now in the next video.
We are going to implement the insertion sort.